<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>la-sophiste on AM</title>
    <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/la-sophiste/</link>
    <description>Recent content in la-sophiste on AM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/la-sophiste/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flan</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/flan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/flan/</guid>
      <description>Flou + Lent = Flan.
What becomes a sound when it is blurred?
Flan tries to answer this question by generating two things: - sharp patterns - sounds corresponding to those patterns
The link between the sounds and the patterns is simple: - triangles: sounds based on triangle waves - circles: sounds based on sine waves - rectangles: sounds based on square waves
A sound is generated for each line of the pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Gears</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/engrenage-musical-musical-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/engrenage-musical-musical-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Création de : Arthur Masson &amp;amp; Gaëtan Hervé
 Musical Gears is an artwork which takes inspiration from the game of life designed by John Horton Conway in 1970.
 The game made Conway instantly famous, but it also opened up a whole new field of mathematical research, the field of cellular automata &amp;hellip; Because of Life&amp;rsquo;s analogies with the rise, fall and alterations of a society of living organisms, it belongs to a growing class of what are called &amp;ldquo;simulation games&amp;rdquo; (games that resemble real life processes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ondes Portées</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ondes-portees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ondes-portees/</guid>
      <description>Ondes portées is an interactive installation which emerges the public in a interactive vector field made of wavy images and sounds.
People&amp;rsquo;s motion acts on the sonor and visual universe, the artwork invites to experiment moves to influence the final composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les murs ont des yeux</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/les-murs-ont-des-yeux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/les-murs-ont-des-yeux/</guid>
      <description>Les murs ont des yeux tracks, stares, fixes, oppresses, inspects, controls the visitor, and questions the la banalization of digital surveillance and how we face it.
This installation is composed of a camera (2D or Kinect) placed under a projection screen, and connected to a tracking software which controls the eye grid in the direction of the visitor.
                                        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasmagorie</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fantasmagorie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fantasmagorie/</guid>
      <description>Fantasmagorie is composed of 8 columns disposed in such way that one can move inside. The spectator placed in the center of the installation can manipulate images and sounds all around him by moving. The image penetrates 6 vertical and horizontal layers on which visuals and sounds criss-corss so that the spectator dives into an immersive world.
I developing my knownledge about shaders thanks to this artwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbres et Visages</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/arbres-et-visages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/arbres-et-visages/</guid>
      <description>Arbres et Visages consists in a photo booth, a small image processing software, a video projector and some trees.
Very simple and efficient installation.
                                                                    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game&#39;n&#39;Watch</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/game-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/game-watch/</guid>
      <description> Game&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;Watch
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My tailer is rich</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/my-tailer-is-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/my-tailer-is-rich/</guid>
      <description>My Tailer is Rich
 This installation is a complete programming interface for a light fresco. I made it with Quartz Composer so that other artists could easily modify the software.
In the end, the software was so complex that it is far from easy to understand it, so this technological choice was probably not the best, but it was a fun technical challenge.
I am pretty happy of the result which we presented at the Pim&amp;rsquo;s, a night club in which I would have never gone otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tranches de Vie</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tranches-de-vie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tranches-de-vie/</guid>
      <description>I enhanced my video processing skills with the artistic installation &amp;ldquo;Tranche de vie&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; (built with OpenCV). I developed this project with openframeworks for a large LED screen.
One of the goal of the installation was to use the special format of the screen which was composed of 5 large vertical stripes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Show&#39;Box</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/showbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/showbox/</guid>
      <description>The Show&amp;rsquo;Box is a karaoke shower box. The idea is simple : one can sing confortably feeling alone under the shower, while being filmed and screened in the large room with the audience! Everything to exhibit in intimacy :-)
I developed the software which enable to select and play a video with subtitles, to overlay the singers on top of it, and to choose patterns for the background. Built with C++ and openframeworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vilaine Ballade</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/vilaine-ballade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/vilaine-ballade/</guid>
      <description>I developed at La Sophiste this interactive video mapping application for La Vilaine Ballade organized by Les Ateliers du Vent in 2012.
The installation was design as a mean for citizens to express how they see the ideal city.
By moving in specific ways, the visitor can interact with the mapped buildings in different modes. One can choose the textures of the buildings, destroy or rebuild them and paint bricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/wisdom/</guid>
      <description>La Sophiste was in charge of VJing for the trance music festival Wisdom.
This was my first video mapping / VJing installation, it required a good amound of work but was worth the effort. Being a VJ for a crowd of thousands of people is fun, and we were really satistied by our work, although everything did not work exactly as expected.
I created an entire VJing app with Quartz Composer which was monitored via midi mapped controlers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>