<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>experiment on AM</title>
    <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/experiment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in experiment on AM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/experiment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Glasses Prototype</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/glasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/glasses/</guid>
      <description>I started building experimental glasses after trying the amazing 3D printed glasses by Quentin Orhant.
First, I created multiple 3D models with Blender. I thought about creating a 3D tool to generate models directly from 2D bezier curves, then I tried Optimaker, then I decided to create my own handcrafted 3D models.
Then I realized that I like minimalistic shapes ; so I did a first 2D test with 3mm poplar plywood sheets and the CNC of the IDLV (http://idlv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spheres</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/spheres/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/spheres/</guid>
      <description>Spheres is a set of algorithms to generate pattern to fold spheres and other geometric shapes.
Those could be used to create nice lamps from a thin layer of wook, cardboard, or from other materials.
I particularly like the orange skin and the flower foldings :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESS</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ess/</guid>
      <description>Collapse + Super Intelligence = Sobriety I imagined the performance Collapse + Super Intelligence = Sobriety as a dialog between multiple artistic mediums in a cinema. This idea is directly taken from OIIO, a concept that I developed years ago with La Sophiste.
The artwork takes life into visual and acoustic procedural illustrations, emerging from an interaction between the sounds, the images and the performer. The artist imagines a creation and initiate it with a midi controler ; the artwork animates, takes life and embodies into sounds and images ; it influence itself, becomes self-sufficient and then inspires the creator who reacts to those new stimuli.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tchack Poum</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tchack-poum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tchack-poum/</guid>
      <description>Tchack Poum is small graphical music box experiment that I made partly from older projects.
It is very minimalistic ; I did not take time to find proper sounds and graphics, and to create an interactive grid to toggle notes and beats.
This is a draft that might, one day, evolve into something bigger&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comme un Dessein</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/comme-un-dessein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 15:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/comme-un-dessein/</guid>
      <description>Festival Maintenant - octobre 2017
Théâtre du Vieux St-Etienne - Rennes (Fr)
  &amp;ldquo;Does the general interest emerges from participative democracy?&amp;rdquo;
 Comme un Dessein echoes this contemporary question by inviting the public to debate and to collaboratively draw at the Maintenant festival. A collective fresco will emerge from this installation thanks to a web interface connected to a vertical plotter at the Vieux St-Etienne theatre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gif Jokey</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/gif-jokey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 17:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/gif-jokey/</guid>
      <description>Gif Jokey (pronounce GJ) is a VJing app based on a gif-o-maton / a machine to build GIFs.
I was inspired by Felix Turner&amp;rsquo;s Bad TV Shader and by getmosh.io and gifpal.com.
A few gifs I created quite quickly:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ili</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ili/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ili/</guid>
      <description>ili is a small generative algorithm which draws a pattern similar to a city map.
I largely took inspiration on the great work of J. Tarbell. I did not implement everything ; I let trails aside in order to keep something very simple and light which I like. Yet, I would like to take some time to further explore the miriads of possiblities which enables this algorithm.

This algorithm is very simple, but many methods can be used to implement it, each having pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flan</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/flan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/flan/</guid>
      <description>Flou + Lent = Flan.
What becomes a sound when it is blurred?
Flan tries to answer this question by generating two things: - sharp patterns - sounds corresponding to those patterns
The link between the sounds and the patterns is simple: - triangles: sounds based on triangle waves - circles: sounds based on sine waves - rectangles: sounds based on square waves
A sound is generated for each line of the pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BrailleRap</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/braillerap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/braillerap/</guid>
      <description>The goal of the BrailleRap project is to use a 3D printer to write braille on a sheet of paper.
A software converts text into braille and gcode instructions to control the nozzle of a 3D printer to print the corresponding dots. A custom printer head was designed with OpenSCAD and 3D printed to hold the perfect pin to obtain better results.
This project took place at the Fabrikarium organized by My Human Kit at Airbus in Toulouse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Gears</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/engrenage-musical-musical-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/engrenage-musical-musical-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Création de : Arthur Masson &amp;amp; Gaëtan Hervé
 Musical Gears is an artwork which takes inspiration from the game of life designed by John Horton Conway in 1970.
 The game made Conway instantly famous, but it also opened up a whole new field of mathematical research, the field of cellular automata &amp;hellip; Because of Life&amp;rsquo;s analogies with the rise, fall and alterations of a society of living organisms, it belongs to a growing class of what are called &amp;ldquo;simulation games&amp;rdquo; (games that resemble real life processes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odyssée Urbaine</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/odyssee-urbaine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/odyssee-urbaine/</guid>
      <description>Robograff - Odyssée Urbaine 2016
Music : Funky DL &amp;amp; Nujabes - Don&amp;rsquo;t even try it
 At the Odyssée Urbaine Festival in 2016, IDLV began a project which was thought at the very beginning of the tipibot story: for the first time, the robot will use a spray paint to draw!
For this project, the collective met children at the Sonia Delaunay primary school and proposed them to draw the nature of their dream : plants, trees, flowers&amp;hellip; Children were involved in a creative process, through the dicovery of an artistic practice and the usage of digital technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper toy</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/paper-toy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/paper-toy/</guid>
      <description>A small tool to easily create paper toys. The interface if minimalist and it could be largely improved, but it can already help building all kinds of objects from simple geometric shapes.
After all, a castle is nothing more than an assembly of cylindres, cones, pyramids and boxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euphony Mapping</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/euphony-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/euphony-mapping/</guid>
      <description> Euphony Mapping
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Crowd</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/interactive-crowd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/interactive-crowd/</guid>
      <description>Interactive crowd This design project is an attempt to provide interaction between a crowd of people and a large scale application (video projection mapping). Interactive installations generally provide controlers to a few individuals (http://pixelpyros.org/).
The idea of Interactive crowd is to provide simple and cheap controlers to anybody in the crowd.
Different versions In the first version, controlers are simple laser LEDs which display a dot on the artwork (typically a video projection on a building) which are tracked with a camera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ondes Portées</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ondes-portees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ondes-portees/</guid>
      <description>Ondes portées is an interactive installation which emerges the public in a interactive vector field made of wavy images and sounds.
People&amp;rsquo;s motion acts on the sonor and visual universe, the artwork invites to experiment moves to influence the final composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romanesco</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/romanesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/romanesco/</guid>
      <description>I always wanted to study and exploit the potential of the internet.
More specifically I am interested in the way people collaborate and create together. Hence I started working on Romanesco, a collaborative drawing application based on an infinite canvas.
The goal of this project is also to bring developers together to create a wide library of diverse drawing tools.
This is a huge hobby project which I developed alone, I see it as an experiment and a proof-of-concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les murs ont des yeux</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/les-murs-ont-des-yeux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/les-murs-ont-des-yeux/</guid>
      <description>Les murs ont des yeux tracks, stares, fixes, oppresses, inspects, controls the visitor, and questions the la banalization of digital surveillance and how we face it.
This installation is composed of a camera (2D or Kinect) placed under a projection screen, and connected to a tracking software which controls the eye grid in the direction of the visitor.
                                        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasmagorie</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fantasmagorie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fantasmagorie/</guid>
      <description>Fantasmagorie is composed of 8 columns disposed in such way that one can move inside. The spectator placed in the center of the installation can manipulate images and sounds all around him by moving. The image penetrates 6 vertical and horizontal layers on which visuals and sounds criss-corss so that the spectator dives into an immersive world.
I developing my knownledge about shaders thanks to this artwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbres et Visages</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/arbres-et-visages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/arbres-et-visages/</guid>
      <description>Arbres et Visages consists in a photo booth, a small image processing software, a video projector and some trees.
Very simple and efficient installation.
                                                                    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game&#39;n&#39;Watch</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/game-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/game-watch/</guid>
      <description> Game&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;Watch
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OIIO</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/oiio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/oiio/</guid>
      <description>OIIO (Opensource Interfaced Inputs / Outputs) is a modular interface concept which aims at establishing a communication between different artistic medias and disciplines.
This concept was developed in response to the emergence of interactive digital art. It is highly related (if not bypassed) by Spacebrew, an open, dynamically re-routable software toolkit for choreographing interactive spaces.
Read the full concept: - OIIO 1 - OIIO 2 - OIIO 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My tailer is rich</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/my-tailer-is-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/my-tailer-is-rich/</guid>
      <description>My Tailer is Rich
 This installation is a complete programming interface for a light fresco. I made it with Quartz Composer so that other artists could easily modify the software.
In the end, the software was so complex that it is far from easy to understand it, so this technological choice was probably not the best, but it was a fun technical challenge.
I am pretty happy of the result which we presented at the Pim&amp;rsquo;s, a night club in which I would have never gone otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tranches de Vie</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tranches-de-vie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tranches-de-vie/</guid>
      <description>I enhanced my video processing skills with the artistic installation &amp;ldquo;Tranche de vie&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; (built with OpenCV). I developed this project with openframeworks for a large LED screen.
One of the goal of the installation was to use the special format of the screen which was composed of 5 large vertical stripes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Show&#39;Box</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/showbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/showbox/</guid>
      <description>The Show&amp;rsquo;Box is a karaoke shower box. The idea is simple : one can sing confortably feeling alone under the shower, while being filmed and screened in the large room with the audience! Everything to exhibit in intimacy :-)
I developed the software which enable to select and play a video with subtitles, to overlay the singers on top of it, and to choose patterns for the background. Built with C++ and openframeworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vilaine Ballade</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/vilaine-ballade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/vilaine-ballade/</guid>
      <description>I developed at La Sophiste this interactive video mapping application for La Vilaine Ballade organized by Les Ateliers du Vent in 2012.
The installation was design as a mean for citizens to express how they see the ideal city.
By moving in specific ways, the visitor can interact with the mapped buildings in different modes. One can choose the textures of the buildings, destroy or rebuild them and paint bricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/wisdom/</guid>
      <description>La Sophiste was in charge of VJing for the trance music festival Wisdom.
This was my first video mapping / VJing installation, it required a good amound of work but was worth the effort. Being a VJ for a crowd of thousands of people is fun, and we were really satistied by our work, although everything did not work exactly as expected.
I created an entire VJing app with Quartz Composer which was monitored via midi mapped controlers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logic Circuit Simulator</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/logic-circuit-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/logic-circuit-simulator/</guid>
      <description>My second year project at ESIR was a logical circuit simulator.
I developed a dynamic version which show of logical signals propagate in the circuits.
The work area is small, but it is possible to navigate on the canvas to create complexe circuits.
I could then build this 4 bits adder :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spick</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/spick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/spick/</guid>
      <description>Spick is probably the second application which I developped in ActionScript.
The goal of this tool is to organize ideas with multiple types of hierarchy. This experiment is similar to mind-mapping apps, but at this time is was not democratized and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about it.
Each text box can be : - simple paragraphs - comments - &amp;ldquo;folders&amp;rdquo; which contains a sub-network of boxes (which can also contain other sub-boxes)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound generator</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/sound-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/sound-generator/</guid>
      <description>This sound generator was one of my very first application. It is very simple, but can theoretically simulate any sound since it is possible to add an &amp;ldquo;infinite&amp;rdquo; amount of sine waves :-)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>