<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English</title>
    <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on English</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://arthurmasson.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/contact/</guid>
      <description>Arthur Masson
arthur.sw@gmail.com
arthurmasson.xyz
Indiens Dans La Ville
idlv.co
facebook.com/IDLVcollectif
La Sophiste
lasophiste.com
facebook.com/collectiflasophiste</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Société Ouverte] Lettre à Xavier</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/societe-ouverte-lettre-a-xavier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/societe-ouverte-lettre-a-xavier/</guid>
      <description>Cher Ksawery,
Je viens juste d’avoir une révélation que je dois absolument te partager.
J’ai récemment rencontré Hugues et les indiens, il me semble que tu connais ces makers fous qui s’appliquent à transmettre leur philosophie du partage issue du monde du libre. Ces bricoleurs bienveillants qui prônent le Do-It-Yourself m’ont enseigné leurs convictions. [que je résumerai grossierement ainsi :
se réapproprier les moyens de production et de transmission, s’impliquer dans des projets pour mieux cerner les tenants et aboutissant de chaque technologie, mieux comprendre les enjeux et avoir un sens plus aiguisé des réalitées, et pour s’accomplir à travers des projets concrets,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gif Jokey</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/gif-jokey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 17:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/gif-jokey/</guid>
      <description>Gif Jokey (pronounce GJ) is a VJing app based on a gif-o-maton / a machine to build GIFs.
I was inspired by Felix Turner&amp;rsquo;s Bad TV Shader and by getmosh.io and gifpal.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tipibot</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tipibot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 17:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tipibot/</guid>
      <description>The Tipibot is an open source vertical plotter to draw images with different tools (pencils, felt pen, marker, spray paint, etc.)
http://idlv.co/robograff/
http://idlv.co/grande-synthe/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDLV.co</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/idlv-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/idlv-co/</guid>
      <description>The website of Indiens Dans La Ville is online!
The minimalist CMS behind this minimalist site is ghost.js.
This node.js framework works well but it lacks of important features : media management (finding, sorting, deleting, resizing, displaying images) and internationalization / multilingual tools.
I used the theme Vapor which you can see in action on Hipster Ghost.
I also used the PhotoSwipe image gallery, very efficient and minimalist, which require a bit of work to set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProBuilder</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/probuilder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/probuilder/</guid>
      <description>I have worked 18 month on ProBuilder, a 3D modeling plugin for Unreal Engine which enables to create 3D objects directly within the UE editor. The goal of this project is to provide a large set of features while remaining a very simple user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ili</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ili/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ili/</guid>
      <description>ili is a small generative algorithm which draws a pattern similar to a city map.
I largely took inspiration on the great work of J. Tarbell. I did not implement everything ; I let trails aside in order to keep something very simple and light which I like. Yet, I would like to take some time to further explore the miriads of possiblities which enables this algorithm.

This algorithm is very simple, but many methods can be used to implement it, each having pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flan</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/flan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/flan/</guid>
      <description>Flou + Lent = Flan.
What becomes a sound when it is blurred?
Flan tries to answer this question by generating two things: - sharp patterns - sounds corresponding to those patterns
The link between the sounds and the patterns is simple: - triangles: sounds based on triangle waves - circles: sounds based on sine waves - rectangles: sounds based on square waves
A sound is generated for each line of the pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Gears</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/engrenage-musical-musical-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/engrenage-musical-musical-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Création de : Arthur Masson &amp;amp; Gaëtan Hervé
 Musical Gears is an artwork which takes inspiration from the game of life designed by John Horton Conway in 1970.
 The game made Conway instantly famous, but it also opened up a whole new field of mathematical research, the field of cellular automata &amp;hellip; Because of Life&amp;rsquo;s analogies with the rise, fall and alterations of a society of living organisms, it belongs to a growing class of what are called &amp;ldquo;simulation games&amp;rdquo; (games that resemble real life processes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative Reflection Platform</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/collaborative-reflection-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/collaborative-reflection-platform/</guid>
      <description>I wrote an article which explains why it is time to create a collaborative reflection platform, and gave some ideas to reach this goal.
This article exists in short version and in long version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper toy</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/paper-toy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/paper-toy/</guid>
      <description>A small tool to easily create paper toys. The interface if minimalist and it could be largely improved, but it can already help building all kinds of objects from simple geometric shapes.
After all, a castle is nothing more than an assembly of cylindres, cones, pyramids and boxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ondes Portées</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ondes-portees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ondes-portees/</guid>
      <description>Ondes portées is an interactive installation which emerges the public in a interactive vector field made of wavy images and sounds.
People&amp;rsquo;s motion acts on the sonor and visual universe, the artwork invites to experiment moves to influence the final composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misst1guett</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/misst1guett/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/misst1guett/</guid>
      <description>I developed misst1guett.com in 2013 for the wonderful illustrator Misst1guett!
The home page displays a pretty drawing, a timeline form the great TimelineJS and some clouds of projects.
Here are a few illustrations of her:
                                                      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasmagorie</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fantasmagorie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fantasmagorie/</guid>
      <description>Fantasmagorie is composed of 8 columns disposed in such way that one can move inside. The spectator placed in the center of the installation can manipulate images and sounds all around him by moving. The image penetrates 6 vertical and horizontal layers on which visuals and sounds criss-corss so that the spectator dives into an immersive world.
I developing my knownledge about shaders thanks to this artwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game&#39;n&#39;Watch</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/game-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/game-watch/</guid>
      <description> Game&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;Watch
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My tailer is rich</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/my-tailer-is-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/my-tailer-is-rich/</guid>
      <description>My Tailer is Rich
 This installation is a complete programming interface for a light fresco. I made it with Quartz Composer so that other artists could easily modify the software.
In the end, the software was so complex that it is far from easy to understand it, so this technological choice was probably not the best, but it was a fun technical challenge.
I am pretty happy of the result which we presented at the Pim&amp;rsquo;s, a night club in which I would have never gone otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tranches de Vie</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tranches-de-vie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tranches-de-vie/</guid>
      <description>I enhanced my video processing skills with the artistic installation &amp;ldquo;Tranche de vie&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; (built with OpenCV). I developed this project with openframeworks for a large LED screen.
One of the goal of the installation was to use the special format of the screen which was composed of 5 large vertical stripes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Show&#39;Box</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/showbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/showbox/</guid>
      <description>The Show&amp;rsquo;Box is a karaoke shower box. The idea is simple : one can sing confortably feeling alone under the shower, while being filmed and screened in the large room with the audience! Everything to exhibit in intimacy :-)
I developed the software which enable to select and play a video with subtitles, to overlay the singers on top of it, and to choose patterns for the background. Built with C++ and openframeworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logic Circuit Simulator</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/logic-circuit-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/logic-circuit-simulator/</guid>
      <description>My second year project at ESIR was a logical circuit simulator.
I developed a dynamic version which show of logical signals propagate in the circuits.
The work area is small, but it is possible to navigate on the canvas to create complexe circuits.
I could then build this 4 bits adder :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arthurmasson.perso</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/arthurmasson-perso/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/arthurmasson-perso/</guid>
      <description>I created a personal website in 2010. At this time, flash was far from being abandoned, it seemed to have a great future !
I enjoyed working with ActionScript 3.0, this language is simple, powerful and somehow portable and complete. Those qualities are rarely met within a single technology. However, this language almost disappeared from the web since it requires to compile, does not give the possibility to distribute the source codes by design and does not respect web standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PG-Lease</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/pg-lease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/pg-lease/</guid>
      <description>I developed a small flash website for PG_Lease, a small brokerage company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comme une fée</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/comme-une-fee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/comme-une-fee/</guid>
      <description>I created an e-commerce website with a flash version and a Joomla / Virtuemart version in 2009.
This job required me to develop different skills : graphic designer, web developer, UX designer etc. This project was intense, very interesting and rewarding :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphic design</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fr/graphic-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fr/graphic-design/</guid>
      <description>For my first year at engineering school, I had fun working on a flash presentation about graphic design for my english course, and this is the result. As you can see, I was not a graphic designer, but I do like graphic design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spick</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/spick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/spick/</guid>
      <description>Spick is probably the second application which I developped in ActionScript.
The goal of this tool is to organize ideas with multiple types of hierarchy. This experiment is similar to mind-mapping apps, but at this time is was not democratized and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about it.
Each text box can be : - simple paragraphs - comments - &amp;ldquo;folders&amp;rdquo; which contains a sub-network of boxes (which can also contain other sub-boxes)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound generator</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/sound-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/sound-generator/</guid>
      <description>This sound generator was one of my very first application. It is very simple, but can theoretically simulate any sound since it is possible to add an &amp;ldquo;infinite&amp;rdquo; amount of sine waves :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/3d/</guid>
      <description>A few of my 3D artworks designed when I was self-learning 3D modeling or working on various video game projects.
                                                                  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>