<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>From1to18hours on AM</title>
    <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/from1to18hours/</link>
    <description>Recent content in From1to18hours on AM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/from1to18hours/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plantoid</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/plantoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/plantoid/</guid>
      <description>Plantoid  Controller and simulator Sources Blender 3D model Server  A controller and simulator for the three Plantoids which will be built for Burning Man 2018.
I created those apps with two objectives in mind: - simulate the plantoid, which are not finished yet, to be able to work on visual effects right away, - have a GUI to control the LED strips: choose visual effects, control which LED will be on and off (not every led of the LED strip must be lighten), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game of Shapes</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/game-of-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/game-of-shapes/</guid>
      <description> Game of Shapes Game of shapes
Shapes generated from a 1D game of life.
1) each rule (group of 3 cells) corresponds to a shape 2) shapes are organised into column, a column corresponds to a serie of similar cells
Rule to shape conversions  000: nothing 001: rectangle 010: circle 011: down triangle 100: horizontal rectangle 101: vertical rectangle 110: small circle 111: up triangle  Controls  space: play / pause animation left / right: go to previous / next rule of the game of life up / down: go to previous / next iteration of the game of life click / drag (on the top most part): go to the iteration corresponding to the position of the mouse  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Avoiding Walk</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/self-avoiding-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/self-avoiding-walk/</guid>
      <description>SAW
Sources
A naïve Self Avoiding Walk algorithm which generates music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Filling Curves</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/space-filling-curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/space-filling-curves/</guid>
      <description>Space Filling Curves is an &amp;ldquo;image based space-filling curve generator&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s a sort of artwork.
 Sources Demo  Drag&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;drop the image of your choice on the canvas to generate a hilbert or gosper curve version.
How does it work? A Space Filling Curve (Hilbert curve or a Gosper curve) is computed from a grayscale image, refined where the image is darker than thredhold.
General idea The image is recusively divided in tiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Société Ouverte] Lettres à Xavier</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/societe-ouverte-lettres-a-xavier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 15:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/societe-ouverte-lettres-a-xavier/</guid>
      <description>Lettre à Ksawery n°1 Cher Ksawery,
Je viens juste d’avoir une révélation que je dois absolument te partager.
J’ai récemment rencontré Hugues et les indiens, il me semble que tu connais ces makers fous qui s’appliquent à transmettre leur philosophie du partage issue du monde du libre. Ces bricoleurs bienveillants qui prônent le Do-It-Yourself m’ont enseigné leurs convictions. [que je résumerai grossierement ainsi :
se réapproprier les moyens de production et de transmission, s’impliquer dans des projets pour mieux cerner les tenants et aboutissant de chaque technologie, mieux comprendre les enjeux et avoir un sens plus aiguisé des réalitées, et pour s’accomplir à travers des projets concrets,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pot de fleurs génératifs</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/pots-de-fleurs-g%C3%A9n%C3%A9ratifs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/pots-de-fleurs-g%C3%A9n%C3%A9ratifs/</guid>
      <description>  Parametric flower pots
 Flower pots programmed with OpenSCAD.
Made with Quentin Orhant for Indiens Dans La Ville.
Thanks to code (it could also be describes with nodes or other means), it is possible to modify the size, the diameters or the number of faces to generate a new object. Once the digital object is created, it can easily be 3D printed.
Sources:  VasesFixed.scad Vase.scad Vase-2.scad  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ili</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ili/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/ili/</guid>
      <description>ili is a small generative algorithm which draws a pattern similar to a city map.
I largely took inspiration on the great work of J. Tarbell. I did not implement everything ; I let trails aside in order to keep something very simple and light which I like. Yet, I would like to take some time to further explore the miriads of possiblities which enables this algorithm.

This algorithm is very simple, but many methods can be used to implement it, each having pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flan</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/flan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/flan/</guid>
      <description>Flou + Lent = Flan.
What becomes a sound when it is blurred?
Flan tries to answer this question by generating two things: - sharp patterns - sounds corresponding to those patterns
The link between the sounds and the patterns is simple: - triangles: sounds based on triangle waves - circles: sounds based on sine waves - rectangles: sounds based on square waves
A sound is generated for each line of the pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Gears</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/engrenage-musical-musical-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/engrenage-musical-musical-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Création de : Arthur Masson &amp;amp; Gaëtan Hervé
 Musical Gears is an artwork which takes inspiration from the game of life designed by John Horton Conway in 1970.
 The game made Conway instantly famous, but it also opened up a whole new field of mathematical research, the field of cellular automata &amp;hellip; Because of Life&amp;rsquo;s analogies with the rise, fall and alterations of a society of living organisms, it belongs to a growing class of what are called &amp;ldquo;simulation games&amp;rdquo; (games that resemble real life processes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper toy</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/paper-toy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/paper-toy/</guid>
      <description>A small tool to easily create paper toys. The interface if minimalist and it could be largely improved, but it can already help building all kinds of objects from simple geometric shapes.
After all, a castle is nothing more than an assembly of cylindres, cones, pyramids and boxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbres et Visages</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/arbres-et-visages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/arbres-et-visages/</guid>
      <description>Arbres et Visages consists in a photo booth, a small image processing software, a video projector and some trees.
Very simple and efficient installation.
                                                                    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OIIO</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/oiio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/oiio/</guid>
      <description>OIIO (Opensource Interfaced Inputs / Outputs) is a modular interface concept which aims at establishing a communication between different artistic medias and disciplines.
This concept was developed in response to the emergence of interactive digital art. It is highly related (if not bypassed) by Spacebrew, an open, dynamically re-routable software toolkit for choreographing interactive spaces.
Read the full concept: - OIIO 1 - OIIO 2 - OIIO 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphic design</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fr/graphic-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/fr/graphic-design/</guid>
      <description>For my first year at engineering school, I had fun working on a flash presentation about graphic design for my english course, and this is the result. As you can see, I was not a graphic designer, but I do like graphic design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spick</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/spick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/spick/</guid>
      <description>Spick is probably the second application which I developped in ActionScript.
The goal of this tool is to organize ideas with multiple types of hierarchy. This experiment is similar to mind-mapping apps, but at this time is was not democratized and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about it.
Each text box can be : - simple paragraphs - comments - &amp;ldquo;folders&amp;rdquo; which contains a sub-network of boxes (which can also contain other sub-boxes)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound generator</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/sound-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/sound-generator/</guid>
      <description>This sound generator was one of my very first application. It is very simple, but can theoretically simulate any sound since it is possible to add an &amp;ldquo;infinite&amp;rdquo; amount of sine waves :-)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>