<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>From1to18months on English</title>
    <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/from1to18months/</link>
    <description>Recent content in From1to18months on English</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 15:06:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/from1to18months/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comme un Dessein</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/comme-un-dessein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 15:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/comme-un-dessein/</guid>
      <description>Festival Maintenant - octobre 2017
Théâtre du Vieux St-Etienne - Rennes (Fr)
  &amp;ldquo;Does the general interest emerges from participative democracy?&amp;rdquo;
 Comme un Dessein echoes this contemporary question by inviting the public to debate and to collaboratively draw at the Maintenant festival. A collective fresco will emerge from this installation thanks to a web interface connected to a vertical plotter at the Vieux St-Etienne theatre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tipibot</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tipibot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 17:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tipibot/</guid>
      <description>The Tipibot is an open source vertical plotter to draw images with different tools (pencils, felt pen, marker, spray paint, etc.)
http://idlv.co/robograff/
http://idlv.co/grande-synthe/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProBuilder</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/probuilder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/probuilder/</guid>
      <description>I have worked 18 month on ProBuilder, a 3D modeling plugin for Unreal Engine which enables to create 3D objects directly within the UE editor. The goal of this project is to provide a large set of features while remaining a very simple user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logo Detection and Identification</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/logo-detection-and-identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 15:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/logo-detection-and-identification/</guid>
      <description>I developed a logo detection and identification system in the context of the European project FIIA, a collaboration between the french research laboratory INRIA and the Icelandic computer vision company Videntifier.
This project was a perfect occasion to put the computer vision theory I learned into practice. During this 18 months I enhanced my skills in OpenCV and Qt, and I coped with engineering project management.
You can read the LDI project presentation for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romanesco</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/romanesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/romanesco/</guid>
      <description>I always wanted to study and exploit the potential of the internet. More specifically I am interested in the way people collaborate and create together. Hence I started working on Romanesco, a collaborative drawing application based on an infinite canvas. The goal of this project is also to bring developers together to create a wide library of diverse drawing tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/wisdom/</guid>
      <description>La Sophiste was in charge of VJing for the trance music festival Wisdom.
This was my first video mapping / VJing installation, it required a good amound of work but was worth the effort. Being a VJ for a crowd of thousands of people is fun, and we were really satistied by our work, although everything did not work exactly as expected.
I created an entire VJing app with Quartz Composer which was monitored via midi mapped controlers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>