<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Idlv on English</title>
    <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/idlv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Idlv on English</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 15:06:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://arthurmasson.xyz/tags/idlv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comme un Dessein</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/comme-un-dessein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 15:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/comme-un-dessein/</guid>
      <description>Festival Maintenant - octobre 2017
Théâtre du Vieux St-Etienne - Rennes (Fr)
  &amp;ldquo;Does the general interest emerges from participative democracy?&amp;rdquo;
 Comme un Dessein echoes this contemporary question by inviting the public to debate and to collaboratively draw at the Maintenant festival. A collective fresco will emerge from this installation thanks to a web interface connected to a vertical plotter at the Vieux St-Etienne theatre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tipibot</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tipibot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 17:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/tipibot/</guid>
      <description>The Tipibot is an open source vertical plotter to draw images with different tools (pencils, felt pen, marker, spray paint, etc.)
http://idlv.co/robograff/
http://idlv.co/grande-synthe/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDLV.co</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/idlv-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/idlv-co/</guid>
      <description>The website of Indiens Dans La Ville is online!
The minimalist CMS behind this minimalist site is ghost.js.
This node.js framework works well but it lacks of important features : media management (finding, sorting, deleting, resizing, displaying images) and internationalization / multilingual tools.
I used the theme Vapor which you can see in action on Hipster Ghost.
I also used the PhotoSwipe image gallery, very efficient and minimalist, which require a bit of work to set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Odyssée Urbaine</title>
      <link>http://arthurmasson.xyz/odyssee-urbaine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://arthurmasson.xyz/odyssee-urbaine/</guid>
      <description>Robograff - Odyssée Urbaine 2016
Music : Funky DL &amp;amp; Nujabes - Don&amp;rsquo;t even try it
 At the Odyssée Urbaine Festival in 2016, IDLV began a project which was thought at the very beginning of the tipibot story: for the first time, the robot will use a spray paint to draw!
For this project, the collective met children at the Sonia Delaunay primary school and proposed them to draw the nature of their dream : plants, trees, flowers&amp;hellip; Children were involved in a creative process, through the dicovery of an artistic practice and the usage of digital technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>